<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sailing on Way Maker Voyages</title>
    <link>http://localhost:59637/tags/sailing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sailing on Way Maker Voyages</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:59637/tags/sailing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experiential Learning: Why It Works—and Why It Belongs in Family Travel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:59637/blog/sample-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:59637/blog/sample-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiential-learning-why-it-worksand-why-it-belongs-in-family-travel&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiential Learning: Why It Works—and Why It Belongs in Family Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the corporate world, experiential learning has become one of the most powerful tools for building strong teams and teaching lessons that actually stick. Instead of sitting in a conference room or listening to another presentation, teams are placed &lt;strong&gt;inside an experience&lt;/strong&gt;—one that requires communication, problem-solving, trust, and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The results speak for themselves. Companies use experiential learning because it works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One More Email</title>
      <link>http://localhost:59637/blog/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:59637/blog/email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;they-say-the-days-are-long-but-the-years-are-short&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They say the days are long, but the years are short&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I always heard that phrase… and nodded along.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now that my wife and I are officially empty nesters, I &lt;strong&gt;feel&lt;/strong&gt; it in a way I never could before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I’m honestly shocked at how fast it all went.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean it was easy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were seasons we weren’t sure we’d survive:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;sleepless nights with a sick child&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;potty training boys (enough said)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the teenage years that tested everyone’s patience and faith&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Somehow, by God’s grace, we were blessed with three incredible kids. They are, without question, what I’m most proud of in this life. And if we’re being honest, most of the credit goes to my wife.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing it Safe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:59637/blog/regret/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:59637/blog/regret/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;throw-off-the-bowlines-a-note-to-high-performers-whove-been-playing-it-safe&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Throw Off the Bowlines”: A Note to High Performers Who’ve Been Playing It Safe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Twenty years from now you will be more disappointed by the things that you didn’t do than by the ones you did do, so throw off the bowlines, sail away from safe harbor, catch the trade winds in your sails. Explore, Dream, Discover.”&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;— Often attributed to Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This has become one of my favorite quotes—but I didn’t discover it until later in life.&#xA;By then, I had already done what many business leaders do well: built a career, chased results, hit targets, and provided for my family. On paper, it all worked. Promotions. Responsibility. Momentum.&#xA;But if I’m honest, I also played it safe for a long time.&#xA;Now I’m trying to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Compass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:59637/blog/compass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:59637/blog/compass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-a-sailors-compass-teaches-us-about-life&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What a Sailors Compass Teaches Us About Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s a moment offshore that every sailor remembers.&#xA;The land disappears. The shoreline fades into a thin line. Then eventually, even that line is gone. No landmarks. No reference points. Just water, sky, and motion.&#xA;It’s in that moment—when there’s nothing left to look at—that the compass quietly becomes the most important object on the boat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not because it’s flashy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not because it demands attention.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But because it is reliable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And that’s exactly why the compass has so much to teach us about life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom,Mentorship, and Avoiding Life&#39;s Hazards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:59637/blog/charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:59637/blog/charts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-from-those-whove-gone-before-you&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning from Those Who’ve Gone Before You&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-nautical-charts-teach-us-about-wisdom-mentorship-and-avoiding-lifes-hidden-hazards&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Nautical Charts Teach Us About Wisdom, Mentorship, and Avoiding Life’s Hidden Hazards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently completed my captain’s license, and one of the most challenging—and surprisingly rewarding—parts of the process was learning how to accurately read nautical charts.&#xA;Not just glancing at them.&#xA;Not just following a line on a screen.&#xA;But truly understanding the symbols, warnings, depths, and hazards hidden in what often looks like open, inviting water.&#xA;It didn’t take long to realize something important:&#xA;Charts don’t exist to tell you where to go.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;They exist to warn you where not to go.&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;And that lesson extends far beyond sailing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
